<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on /dump</title>
    <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on /dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;http://danielcefram.com&#34;&gt;Daniel Cefram&lt;/a&gt; 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 14:46:53 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.danielcefram.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrated to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/migrated-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 14:46:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/migrated-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Ghost for quite sometime already, and my only opensource project in github that was starred by non-collegues is a Ghost theme that I made for my blog. But times has changed, which some of you who are avid readers of my blog might have noticed, my financial situation requires me to be a little more stringent&amp;hellip; which also meant that I had to downgrade my VPS.
Ghost did well as a blogging platform, but the reasources it consumed, particularly RAM, was just too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months in</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/six-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 06:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/six-months-in/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post quite late, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to recall the outstanding events for this month.
Regional Assembly Day(s) We attended our first Regional Assembly together this month, and the topics were really good. The video drama however was what I would call &amp;ldquo;outstanding&amp;rdquo;. It &amp;rsquo;s something that my fragile brain (ie. I have bad memory) could easily remember&amp;hellip; even the line of one of the PoV (Point of View character) who said &amp;ldquo;Pag nabenta ko na ito, mabibili na namin ang apartment na gusto namin&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fifth</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/the-fifth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 08:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/the-fifth/</guid>
      <description>Quick update about our fifth month together.
A visit to the Chiropractor I experienced two seizures this month, one was when I was driving back to work and the the other was during one of the midweek meetings wherein I had an assignment. It was quite embarrassing to be honest since I did make a scene at the kingdom hall XD.
We already went to multiple doctors, but we were not able to get any definitive reason as to why my migraine occurs, and as to why does it go into such an extent that I experience seizures&amp;hellip; So we decided to try out chiropractic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May the Fourth be with... us</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/may-the-fourth-be-with-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 05:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/may-the-fourth-be-with-us/</guid>
      <description>It is the fourth month of being together! &amp;lt;3
It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy month, and a really stressful one (financially). But let me break it down the usual way :)
Certification exams and their awful exam system So, my wife was sent to Singapore by her company to take important certification exam which I believe would propel her worth in the company by a mile :D The cool part is&amp;hellip; she didn&amp;rsquo;t even review well, in that I mean, I saw her review only once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three for thought</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/three-for-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 05:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/three-for-thought/</guid>
      <description>We just entered the 3rd month of being together, and a lot has happened, both positive and negative. I&amp;rsquo;ll start off with the positive:
Successful JW Broadcasting We just hosted our group&amp;rsquo;s broadcasting for this month, and everything went smoothly. What I like about it being hosted on our place is that we were sure to watch the broadcasting of the month :)

The second broadcasting within the month&amp;rsquo;s time period wasn&amp;rsquo;t hosted on our place, but we still went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second month in one roof</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/the-second-month-in-one-roof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 15:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/the-second-month-in-one-roof/</guid>
      <description>As workaholics, our second month was a busy one. Nevertheless, we were able to squeeze in some quality time together&amp;hellip; which we would like to document on this blog :D
The TV We finally bought a television this month, courtesy of our friend Sheryl. She lent us her credit card since Abenson got a &amp;ldquo;0% interest rate on installment&amp;rdquo; promo for HSBC cardholders, so we thought about taking advantage of that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first month of our journey</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/the-first-month-of-our-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/the-first-month-of-our-journey/</guid>
      <description>#breakfastdiary, schedule adjustments, cash burn
The three keywords that sticks out for our first month together :D
breakfastdiary We started to document our mornings with an instagram post of what we eat during breakfast. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a &amp;lsquo;record&amp;rsquo; just to keep track of what to cook next ;)
I still hope that we would be able to continue it and make #breakfastdiary a thing even though we weren&amp;rsquo;t able to continue doing so for the past week or so due to our tight work schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When we tie the knot</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/when-we-tie-the-knot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/when-we-tie-the-knot/</guid>
      <description>Wedding. It&amp;rsquo;s my wedding day today.
To be honest, I am writing this blog post way past my actual wedding day, and through the power of editing the post date&amp;hellip; the blog post will appear as if I published this post at the day of my wedding :D
This is obviously a big milestone for us, and the fact that I now have somebody to travel with me on this journey of uncertainties makes things a little settling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Start</title>
      <link>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/a-new-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 07:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.danielcefram.com/blog/a-new-start/</guid>
      <description>I decided to restart my blog yet again, and this time I&amp;rsquo;m planning to just document my thoughts at least every month. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to getting this goal done, specially with the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m getting married in 2~3 weeks time!&amp;hellip; Which means that I might actually have more things to write about :D
A lot has happened since last year. I clocked a lot of extra hours of work, for the preparation of my wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>